My friend said
He didn't smoke.
Don't worry about
lung cancer?
This concept
You have to update.
Don't think you're safe if you don't smoke
Many lung cancer patients
Never smoked a cigarette
Hu Naiwen starts his lecture
I am your old friend
Doctor Hu
I want to share this episode with you
1.Not just a cough! 5 signs your lungs are asking for help
2.Lung cancer has no symptoms in the early stage, so check a place on your finger
3.5 minutes a day, 1 movement to strengthen the lungs
4.Lung obstruction may lead to cancer! 2 fruits to nourish the lungs and prevent obstruction
5.3 things that can harm your lungs that you encounter every day
Not just a cough! 5 signs your lungs are asking for help
Beautiful wife
Did you know
In Taiwan,
one person dies every fifty minutes.
Died of lung cancer
He has been the No. 1 cause of death
from cancer for 20 consecutive years.
And not just in Taiwan
Lung cancer mortality worldwide
It is the highest among all cancers.
Why do people with lung cancer
So close to death
Because its initial symptoms
It is not obvious
It's easy to think it's just a cold
Nearly 75% of patients
They didn't find out until the 4th issue
Missed
the golden treatment period
So if you want to prevent lung cancer
The most important thing is
Discover its abnormality early
How to know
There are five signs
Cough, wheezing, chest tightness, chest pain
Weight loss and hoarseness
First sign: cough
It is the most common symptom of lung cancer
Especially long-term cough
There is blood in the sputum
This is your lungs sending you
an alarm.
Traditional Chinese Medicine says fèi zhǔ qì (Transliteration)
Tōng diào shuǐ dào de(Transliteration)
If thefèi qì(Transliteration)are damaged
HisJīn yè(Transliteration)
There's no way it can work properly
If you find yourself coughing
More than 3 weeks
If you haven't recovered yet
You have to be careful
Don't put it off any longer.
Go get a checkup right away.
The second sign: shortness of breath
You used to be able to walk fast
Now I feel out of breath after climbing to the fifth floor
This is insufficient lung Qi
Lung Qi deficiency
This causes the blood circulation to deteriorate.
The third sign: chest tightness or chest pain
Common cold
It won't cause chest tightness or pain
But if you breathe
Feeling very oppressive
Even a dull pain
Then we need to be more vigilant
The fourth sign: weight loss
You obviously didn't lose weight.
But inexplicably
lost a lot of weight
Don't be too happy
You thought you were thin
It may be abnormal metabolism of the lungs
Or the tumor is already growing.
The fifth sign is hoarseness.
If you continue to be hoarse
The voice becomes deeper
Be careful if it's more than two weeks.
You have 3 or more symptoms
Check it out now
See a doctor immediately
Maybe your lungs are telling you
SOS SOS Help!
Lung cancer has no symptoms in the early stages
A specific area on the finger to check
My friend said
He didn't smoke.
Don't worry
Lung cancer?
This concept
You have to update.
Don't think you're safe if you don't smoke
Many lung cancer patients
Never smoked a cigarette
Especially the sisters
According to research
Women with lung cancer
More than 90% have never smoked
Oh, really.
Whether you smoke or not
Don't take it lightly
Early stage lung cancer
Difficult to detect obvious symptoms
But there is a small detail
If you notice that the tips
of your fingers
are slightly swollen
and
curved downward
somewhat
like a spoon
this is called 'nail clubbing'
If
this kind of nail clubbing
really occurs
It may be due to long-term lack of oxygen in the lungs
or chronic lung disease
Or a lung tumor
Related phenomena
What is the relationship
between
swollen fingers and lung cancer?
Come, let me tell you
In ancient Greece
In the West,
there is a figure known as the Father of Medicine
Hippocrates
He said
of fingers is related to the pathology
of lungs and heart.
Like lung cancer, tuberculosis
Chronic lung disease
May appear
This so-called nail clubbing
So don't ignore all the little changes
in your body.
Even if you don't cough or wheeze
Check your health regularly
Pay attention to this condition on your fingers
5 minutes a day, 1 movement to open up thefèi jīng(Transliteration)
Want to prevent lung cancer
In addition to staying away from smoking
Is there any other way to nourish the lungs?
Strengthen lung function
Exercises that can be used to produce sound
To strengthen the lungs
Ah, sound
Is it singing?
Singing, singing, singing
No
It's not that sound
It makes a sound
Sī (Transliteration) method
This method
It is a Taoist method of vocalization.
It can help move air through the lungs
Increase lung capacity
Improve the elasticity of the alveoli.
Helps breathe in fresh air
Expel foul air
Then let's do it together
Sit back against the chair
Put your hands on your thighs.
Slowly raise your hands
Breathe in
When your hands reach the top of your head
Turn your hands over
Palms facing the ceiling
Then exhale
When exhaling
It makes a Sī (Transliteration)sound
Feel the expansion of the chest
Keep your mouth as closed as possible
Keep the sound inside
At the end of exhalation
Hands on thighs
Breathe normally
This exercise can be done 20 times a day
When to do it?
It is best to do it
between 5 and 7 in the morning.
Because it ismǎo shí (Transliteration)
mǎo shí (Transliteration)is the time to nourish the lungs
Lung obstruction may lead to cancer
Pears and their ability to moisturize the lungs and prevent obstruction
Beautiful wife, do you know
What fruit is good for the lungs?
Let me take a guess
It should be pear
You are indeed someone who often watches my show.
Not only pears but also apples
According to the journal Thoracic
There is a study in it showing
He said the polyphenols in apples and pears
Has anti-inflammatory effects
Can remove free radicals in the body
Protect lung tissue
Reduce inflammation in the lungs
This will enable
Prevent lung obstruction
That lung obstruction
Not well controlled
Will it turn into lung cancer?
That's right
You have a very smart question.
Research shows
Patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease
Risk of getting lung cancer
Twice as much as the average person
Meaning
If the lungs are severely blocked
It may even develop into cancer
The mortality rate will also increase
Especially now the air
Its quality is getting worse
The so-called PM2.5
Fine particles of air pollution
Breathe it into your lungs every day
Just silently
It's harming our lungs
Moms
When Momsgo to the market to buy fruit
Pear ,Apple
Buy it up
Keep your lungs healthy for the whole family
Buy insurance for the whole family
The benefits of pears
Moisturizes the lungs and relieves cough
Qīng rè huà tán (Transliteration)
Especially suitable for cough with little phlegm
Dry throat
People with hoarse voice
Apple can nourish the lungs
Enhances immunity
It is good for people
with chronic cough or asthma.
3 major lung damage factors
You come into contact with it every day
Risk of lung cancer
Far beyond your imagination
There are three risk factors
Hidden in your life
Smoke,Air Pollution,Fragrance
More contact
It may quietly hurt your lungs
How to prevent lung cancer?
The first one
Keep the smoke away from you
First of all, of course, don't smoke.
And also
Try not to breathe secondhand smoke
Did you know
Secondhand smoke may be
harmful than smoking yourself
I'll just smoke by myself from now on.
There are studies showing that
Women because their husbands smoke
Chances of getting lung cancer
That's twice as much as the average person.
For your wife
Children's health
There are people smoking.
Really, I'm craving for cigarettes
Go outside to smoke
But
You smoke outside
Others will breathe in secondhand smoke
So it’s best not to smoke.
Better, right?
Do you understand?
My beautiful wife said
She said she called you
It's best to quit smoking.
Don't hurt others, okay?
Second, stay away from air pollution
Choose the right time and place to exercise
Exercise protects your lungs
So when is the best time
to exercise?
Before going to work at nine in the morning
When there weren't so many cars
Go to exercise
The air quality is slightly better
is slightly better
What to do if you don’t have time to exercise in the morning
Exercise at night
when there is less traffic
That's OK.
A lot of little girls
Like to be at home
Use that fragrance
Feeling very comfortable
Such a time
Is it harmful to the body?
That's right
This is the last lung-damaging factor
to watch out for.
Girls!
Are you someone who likes to use essential oils?
Choose the ingredients.
As natural as possible is better
Why?
Many synthetic fragrances
Artificial essential oils
Or it has chemical ingredients
Those scented candles
After burning, it will produce
Volatile organic compounds
Long-term inhalation
Increases the risk of cancer
In addition to fragrance and essential oils
Perfume Cosmetics Candles
Also choose natural ingredients
Will not harm your health
Indoor fragrance can be used
Aroma Stone
Or pure plant essential oils
This reduces the release of harmful gases
When buying candles
You can choose
Beeswax Soy Wax
These natural materials
Fragrance-free
Better for health
Choose cosmetics
The brand with strict quality control
Or an organic brand
More secure
Then I'll hurry home and take off my makeup
Can reduce some damage
Yeah, like this
This helps reduce the risk
of your skin absorbing harmful substances
Make you healthier
Friends who like this video
Please click below the video
"Super thanks" for donating to support us
Your support
We all received it.